Guide to the Derrick A. Bell, Jr. Papers MC.138
New York University Archives
- ADDITIONAL ACCESSIONS: 99-008 & 00-004
  - American Library Association, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 17)
  - Charlotte NAACP, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 18)
  - Speech File: Washington, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 19)
  - Speech File: Detroit, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 20)
  - Southern Connecticut State College, 1995-1996 (Box 97, Folder 21)
  - Chinese for Affirmative Action 1996 Annual Dinner, Keynote (Box 97, Folder 22)
  - The Culture of Choice in Law and Policy, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 23)
  - Washburn University Law Journal, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 24)
  - University of Maryland-Baltimore, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 26)
  - Notre Dame Law School BLSA, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 27)
  - NYU Black Literary Week, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 28)
  - Olmos Lecture, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 29)
  - UC Santa Barbara, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 30)
  - Florida Education Fund, 1995-1996 (Box 97, Folder 31)
  - Books & Books, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 32)
  - Root-Tilden Colloquium, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 33)
  - Unified Court System Black History Month, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 34)
  - Rutgers-Newark (Hisotry), 1996 (Box 97, Folder 35)
  - D.C. 37 - Reading, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 36)
  - Hobart and William Smith Colleges, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 37)
  - NYU Institute of the Humanities, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 38)
  - Syracuse University, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 39)
  - BET Weekend, 1995-1996 (Box 97, Folder 40)
  - Clarion University, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 41)
  - MLA Conference, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 42)
  - Gallatin School Senior Symposium, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 43)
  - SEF Conference, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 44)
  - New York Theological School, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 45)
  - Cornell University (cancelled), 1995 (Box 97, Folder 46)
  - New York Book Fair to Help the Homeless "Meet the Authors" Dinner, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 47)
  - Akron University, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 49)
  - Lecture ABFAS Awards Luncheon, 1996 (Box 97, Folder 50)
  - DB Birthday Tribute, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 51)
  - J.L. Turner Legal Associates Annual Scholarship Banquet, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 52)
  - Samford University, Cumberland School of Law, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 53)
  - Voters for Change, 1994 (Box 97, Folder 54)
  - College of Arts and Science Scholars Lecture Series, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 55)
  - Toussaint Institute, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 56)
  - University of Michigan Law School Symposium, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 57)
  - Million Man March, 1995 (Box 97, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence: Professional and Personal, 1987-1989 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042276942
  - Correspondence: Professional and Personal, 1996 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Professional and Personal, 1996 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Professional and Personal, 1996 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Professional and Personal, 1996 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Professional and Personal, 1996 (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Professional and Personal, 1996 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Recent Correspondence, 1983-1996 (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Barristers Dinner (San Francisco), 1994-1997 (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - NYU Correspondence, 1995 (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - National Voting Rights Institute, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042276959
  - Fulani Show, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Amherst College, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - MLK Library, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Seattle, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Black Men Writers Newark, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Goddard-Riverside Author Dinner, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Pittsburgh, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Columbia University (Scott Matheney), 1996 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Haywood Burns Memorial Bar of City of New York, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - John Marshall Law School, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Chicago, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - Trinity Church - Chicago, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - Henrietta Marie Project, 1996-1997 (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - UNC Charlotte, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 15)
  - Cambridge Forum, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 16)
  - Urban League of Oklahoma City, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 17)
  - Loyola at Los Angeles, 1996-1997 (Box 99, Folder 18)
  - Black Heritage Reference Center, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 19)
  - James Weldon Johnson Foundation, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 20)
  - Charlotte Black Lawyers Annual Scholarship Dinner, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 21)
  - Paul Robeson Tribute Book, 1996 (Box 99, Folder 22)
  - Gospel Psalms draft, 1995 (Box 99, Folder 23)
  - Gospel Choirs Permissions, Final Edits, 1995-1996 (Box 99, Folder 24)
  - Articles By and About Bell, 1973-1991 (Box 99, Folder 25)
  - General Material: Gospel Choirs, 1987-1994 (Box 99, Folder 26)
  - Camp James Weldon Johnson Reunion, 1995 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042276967
  - MacDowell Colony, 1995 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Shippensburg University Lecture, 1995 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - University of Oklahoma - Ninth Annual Conference on Race & Ethnicity (San Antonio), 1995-1997 (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Speech File: Dallas, 1996 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Speech File: Miami, 1996 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Speech File: St. James Presbyterian Church, NYC, 1996 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Speech File: Boston, 1996 (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Speech File: Philadelphia, 1996 (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - Ellison Reading, 1996 (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - Pace Law School Commencement, 1996 (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - Partnership - Drugs Panel, 1996 (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Casper Sitcom Joyce Ashley, 1992 (Box 100, Folder 13)
  - Wayne State Labor Conference, 1996 (Box 100, Folder 14)
  - St. James Presbyterian Church Profile, W. Haywood Burns, 1996 (Box 100, Folder 15)
  - The Ford Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 100, Folder 16)
  - Archives: NYU, Schomburg, 1993-1995 (Box 100, Folder 17)
  - Lisa Kelly, 1994-1996 (Box 100, Folder 18)
  - Gospel Choirs, 1995 (Box 100, Folder 19)
  - Confronting Authority, 1992-1995 (Box 100, Folder 20)
  - Mumia Abu-Jamal, 1995 (Box 100, Folder 21)
  - Edmonds, 1989-1995 (Box 100, Folder 22)
  - Essence Magazine article: "The New Move to the Right", 1995 (Box 100, Folder 23)
  - Faces - Film Rights, 1993-1994 (Box 100, Folder 24)
  - Final Fate Contract, 1995 (Box 100, Folder 25)
  - Constitutional Law Back File, 1995 (Box 100, Folder 26)
  - Robert Projansky, 1996 (Box 100, Folder 27)
  - Constitutional Law Class Records, 1995 (Box 100, Folder 28)
  - Stephen Greenwald, 1992-1994 (Box 100, Folder 29)
  - Jones Sisters, 1994 (Box 100, Folder 30)
  - Minority Faculty CV's, 1992-1993 (Box 100, Folder 31)
  - The Nation - Book on Race, 1980-1995 (Box 100, Folder 32)
  - "Personal Places" (Zubin Shroff Photographer), 1995 (Box 100, Folder 33)
  - Current Writing Projects - General, 1993 (Box 100, Folder 34)
  - Black Leadership Commission on AIDS, 1993-1994 (Box 100, Folder 35)
  - Kessler Projects, 1994 (Box 100, Folder 36)
  - Clippings, 1989-1996 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042276975
  - Clippings, 1994-1997 (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1995-1997 (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1994-1995 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Women as Salvation of Race, Comments and Miscellaneous, 1991-1995 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - SCDM (Current Constitutional Issues), 1995-1996 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Issues of Black Chronicle, undated (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Toussaint Institute, 1994-1995 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Professor D. Marvin Jones, University of Miami: Tenure, 1988-1996 (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - Economics, 1992-1995 (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - From C.W. Bennett, 1990 (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - Nagae-Lum, Peggy, 1993 (Box 101, Folder 12)
  - Course Materials (Student Papers) RESTRICTED, 1987-1996 (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 101, Folder 14)
  - Jobs and Genocide, 1989-1995 (Box 101, Folder 15)
  - Economic Data, 1992-1995 (Box 101, Folder 16)
  - Constitutional Law Evaluations, 1995 (Box 101, Folder 17)
  - Constitutional Law Evaluations, 1993 (Box 101, Folder 18)
  - Constitutional Law Evaluations, 1997 (Box 101, Folder 19)
  - Civil Rights at the Crossroads Evaluations, 1992 (Box 101, Folder 20)
  - Constitutional Law Evaluations, 1993 (Box 101, Folder 21)
  - Constitutional Law Evaluations, 1997 (Box 101, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042276983
  - NYU Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - January, 1997 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - February, 1997 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - March, 1997 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - April, 1997 (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - May, 1997 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - June, 1997 (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - July, 1997 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - August, 1997 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042276991
  - September, 1997 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Scholarship on Higher Education Sept. 11, 1997 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - November, 1997 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - November, 1997 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - December, 1997 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - January, 1998 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - February, 1998 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - March, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042277007
  - April, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - May, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - June, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - July, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - August, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - September, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - October, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - November, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - December, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Black Books Plus, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042277015
  - The African American Experience in Higher Education, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Claremont McKenna College, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Bloomsburg University, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Root-Tilden-Snow Scholarship Program, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Essay for Seattle University Law School, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Duke University MLK, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - 13th Annual Black Man Think Tank, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - Emmanuel Baptist Church, 1997 (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - University of Delaware, 1997 (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - Cenotap - Queens, 1997 (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - NPA Task Force, 1996-1997 (Box 105, Folder 14)
  - Kent State University, 1997 (Box 105, Folder 15)
  - Travel/Lecture Fees Outstanding, 1996 (Box 105, Folder 16)
  - Florida International University, 1997-1998 (Box 105, Folder 17)
  - APA Speech, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 18)
  - Students' National Day of Action to Defend Affirmative Action, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 19)
  - Northeast People of Color Conference, 1997-1998 (Box 105, Folder 20)
  - New Politics, 1997-1998 (Box 105, Folder 21)
  - Derrick Bell Dinner, 1997-1998 (Box 105, Folder 22)
  - Jackie Robinson Foundation, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 23)
  - Loren Miller Bar Association, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 24)
  - D.C. Vertigo, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 25)
  - Philadelphia, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 26)
  - Anti-Bias Committee, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 27)
  - Central Michigan University, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 28)
  - Center for Study of Diversity in Teaching and Learning, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 29)
  - NYU Faculty Network, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 30)
  - NAACP Freedom Fund Dinner, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 31)
  - Chicago Book Expo, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 32)
  - San Francisco (Marcus Books on 21st), 1998 (Box 105, Folder 33)
  - NYU Law Teaching Seminar, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 34)
  - Inroads/NYC, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 35)
  - Theatre Works USA Monday, July 13 (Mark Reception), 1998 (Box 105, Folder 36)
  - Schenley High School Reunion, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 37)
  - Florida State University (Black Studies Program New Perspectives Lecture Series), 1998 (Box 105, Folder 38)
  - Just the Beginning Foundation Black Federal Judges, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 39)
  - Henrietta Marie - Rockford, IL, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 40)
  - Appleseed Reception, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 41)
  - Derrick Bell Lecture, 1997-1998 (Box 105, Folder 42)
  - HLS Protest Celebration, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 43)
  - MacDowell Colony, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 45)
  - AFCSME Convention, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 46)
  - Ghost Ranch (New Mexico), 1998 (Box 105, Folder 47)
  - Texas Bill of Rights Project, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 48)
  - Stetson University, Rev. Jeff Rogers, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 49)
  - Johnson C. Smith University, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 50)
  - Davidson College, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 51)
  - NYU Enrichment Program, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 52)
  - Meet the Author Dinners, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 53)
  - Partnership for Homeless Annual Gala, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 54)
  - NYU Celebrates Africana Studies, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 55)
  - High Tea Party, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 56)
  - Reynolds News Service, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 57)
  - AALS Conference New Orleans, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042277023
  - Thulani Davis, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - University of Tulsa, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Impeachment, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Ohio Northern University, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - George School Jodi Soloman Agency Affirmative Action, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Black History Month Choir Program, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Authors Guild Meeting, Michael Chabon Reading, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - University of Puget Sound, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - Florida State University, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - Columbia Law School Women of Color Conference, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - National Conference - Center for Study of Diversity in Teaching and Learning, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Roz Burrough, 1994 (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - Washington University (St. Louis), 1999 (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - Columbia Black Students, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 15)
  - PBS Inside the Law (NYU), 1999 (Box 106, Folder 16)
  - Martin Luther King Forum, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 17)
  - Reading and Reception, 1998 (Box 106, Folder 18)
  - John Brown Day, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 19)
  - ABFAS Awards Luncheon, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 20)
  - Peggy Davis Conference, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 21)
  - Freedom House (Boston), 1999 (Box 106, Folder 22)
  - Museum for African Art Gala Benefit, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 23)
  - Symposium on Affirmative Action (Harvard Medical), 1999 (Box 106, Folder 24)
  - Comparative Human Relations, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 25)
  - Legal Aid of New York, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 26)
  - California, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 27)
  - Metropolitan Baptist Church, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 28)
  - Gender Talks, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 29)
  - Essence Essay, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 30)
  - Brunch (Tarrytown House), 1999 (Box 106, Folder 31)
  - Alabama State University, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 32)
  - Bucknell University, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 33)
  - NYU Faculty Seminar, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 34)
  - Century Foundation (breakfast), 1999 (Box 106, Folder 35)
  - Matthew Tobriner Lecture at Hastings College, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 36)
  - UC Davis, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 37)
  - Denver University Law School, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 38)
  - Harvard Law School Saturday School, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 39)
  - NYU Enrichment, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 40)
  - Fountain of Pembroke Pines, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 41)
  - Medgar Evers College Commencement, 1998 (Box 106, Folder 42)
  - Dennison College (Ohio), 1999 (Box 106, Folder 43)
  - Derrick Bell Lecture, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 44)
  - Higgenbotham Memorial Lecture, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 45)
  - Meet the Author Dinner, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 46)
  - Muhlenberg College, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 47)
  - Readings for Lawyering Theory Workshop, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 48)
  - Lawyering Theory Workshop, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 49)
  - Trinity College, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 50)
  - Seminar, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 51)
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE (Accession 03-008)
  - January, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - February, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - March, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - April, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - May, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - June, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - July, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - August, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - September, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - October, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - November, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - December, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 12)
- SERIES II: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (Accession 03-008)
  - Tobriner Memorial Lecture, Oct 1999 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042277148
  - AALS - SALT (New Orleans), Jan 2002 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - King Birthday, Jan 2002 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - NYU Colloquium, Feb 2002 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Authors Guild's Council Meeting, Feb 2002 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Network Inc. (Louisville), Feb 2002 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - ASU West, Feb 2002 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Lipton Hall, Mar 2002 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Bloomsbury - London, Mar 2002 (Box 108, Folder 9)
  - Federation of Community (Cleveland), Apr 2002 (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - Annual Blapa Dinner, Apr 2002 (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - Brunch at Jezebel's, Apr 2002 (Box 108, Folder 12)
  - Dedication of Courtroom, Apr 2002 (Box 108, Folder 13)
  - Auction Dinner, Apr 2002 (Box 108, Folder 14)
  - Bloomsbury, USAA: Sales Conference, Apr 2002 (Box 108, Folder 15)
  - James McBride, May 2002 (Box 108, Folder 16)
  - African American Studies Picnic, May 2002 (Box 108, Folder 17)
  - NY County Lawyer - Marty Copleman, Jun 2002 (Box 108, Folder 18)
  - New School Swayduck Aud., Jun 2002 (Box 108, Folder 19)
  - Tanglewood, Jul 2002 (Box 108, Folder 20)
  - Dinner - Jay and Christine Harris, Aug 2002 (Box 108, Folder 21)
  - Halifax Tour, Sep 2002 (Box 108, Folder 22)
  - Connecticut College, Sep 2002-Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 23)
  - NYU Installation of John Sexton, Sep 2002 (Box 108, Folder 24)
  - Providence Booksellers (Brown Univ.), Sep 2002 (Box 108, Folder 25)
  - New England Booksellers Conference, Sep 2002 (Box 108, Folder 26)
  - Xavier University (Cincinnati), Sep 2002 (Box 108, Folder 27)
  - Law Clerk's Speakers Program, Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 28)
  - Bonhoeffer Lecture Series, Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 29)
  - NYU Concert, Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 30)
  - Stetson College (Daytona, FL), Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 31)
  - HUE-MAN Experience, Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 32)
  - "Blackonomics" WDBZ-AM (Cinncinati, OH), Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 33)
  - Syracuse University, Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 34)
  - Cambridge - Harvard, Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 35)
  - Cambridge - Harvard Law School, Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 36)
  - Barnes & Noble, Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 37)
  - Chicago, Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 38)
  - Chicago/Milwaukee, Oct 2002 (Box 108, Folder 39)
  - Milwaukee/Detroit, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 40)
  - Detroit/New York, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 41)
  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 42)
  - Derrick Bell Lecture, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 43)
  - Cleveland - John Begala, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 44)
  - Cleveland, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 45)
  - Philadelphia, Nov2002 (Box 108, Folder 46)
  - Pittsburgh, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 47)
  - New York, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 48)
  - Washington, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 49)
  - Vancouver, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 50)
  - Seattle, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 51)
  - Portland, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 52)
  - Los Angeles, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 53)
  - San Francisco, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 54)
  - London, Nov 2002 (Box 108, Folder 55)
  - Dallas, Dec 2002 (Box 108, Folder 56)
  - Kansas City, Dec 2002 (Box 108, Folder 57)
  - St. Louis, Dec 2002 (Box 108, Folder 58)
  - African Canadian Legal Clinic, Dec 2002 (Box 108, Folder 59)
  - Charles Olgetree at 50, Dec 2002 (Box 108, Folder 60)
  - Goddard Riverside, Dec 2002 (Box 108, Folder 61)
- SERIES III: SUBJECT FILES (Accession 03-008)
  - Jefferson, Thomas, 1998-1999 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042277155
  - Patterson, Orlando, 1994 (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, undated (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - "Constitutional Issues", Spring 1999 (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Get Well File - Hospitalization for Pneumonia, Fall 1997 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Labels/Copies, 1998 (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Stuart Educational Leadership Group, Inc., Jan 10, 1998 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Howard Thurman Birthday (cancelled), Nov 20, 1997 (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - NYU Law Review, Jun 30, 1997 (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - Jewel Bell Fund, 1992-1995 (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - Photo Collection: Bell Lecture on Race in American Society, Nov 4, 1999 (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - Williams, Pat, undated (Box 109, Folder 12)
  - NYU Press, Apr 2003 (Box 109, Folder 13)
  - Jewel Bell Memorial Material, 1990-1991 (Box 109, Folder 14)
  - "Space Traders" (Trey Ellis), 1994 (Box 109, Folder 15)
  - Geneva 5, 1990-1997 (Box 109, Folder 16)
  - Thurman, Howard, 1976 (Box 109, Folder 17)
  - Relations between Black and Jewish Communities, 1982-1994 (Box 109, Folder 18)
  - Essence Magazine, 1996 (Box 109, Folder 19)
- SERIES V: BOOK MATERIALS (Accession 03-008)
  - Faces at the Bottom Well, 1992 (Box 109)
  - Confronting Authority: Reflections of an Ardent Protestor, 1994 (Box 109)
  - Gospel Choirs, 1996 (Box 109)
  - Afrolantica Legacies, 1998 (Box 109)
  - Ethical Ambition: Living a Life of Meaning and Worth, 2002 (Box 109)
  - Ethical Ambition (Korean Translation), 2003 (Box 109)
  - Von der Kunst erfolgreich zu leben (German), undated (Box 109)
- PUBLICATIONS AND LAW CASES (Boxes 110-119)(See boxes 118 and 119 for works by Bell)
  - Law Cases
    - Cases, 1953-1967 (Box 110)
      Barcode: 31142042277049
      Scope and Contents
      - Alabama State Board of Ed v. Dixon, St. John, 1961 - Brief for Respondent in Opposition
      - Alabama State Board of Ed vs. Dixon, St. John, 1961 - Petition
      - Anderson, Lewis Llyod vs. State of Alabama, 1960 - Petitioner's Brief
      - Anderson, Lewis Lloyd v. State of Alabama, 1960 - Petitioner's Reply Brief
      - Anderson, W.G. v. City of Albany, Georgia - Brief for Appellants, Appeals
      - Armstrong, Dwight v. Board of Ed, City of Birmingham, Alabama - Brief for Appellants
      - Austin, Christine v. State of Mississippi - Appendix Brief for Appellants
      - Austin, Christine v. State of Mississippi - Brief for Appellants
      - Avent, John Thomas, etc. v. State of N. Carolina, 1960 - Petition
      - Avent, John Thomas v. State of N. Carolina & Lombard, Rudolph v. State of Louisiana & Gober, James v. City of Birmingham & Shuttlesworth, F.L. v. City of Birmingham & Peterson, James Richard v. City of Greenville, 1962 - Brief for USA
      - Bailey, Samuel v. Joe T. Patterson - Brief for Appellants
      - Baldwin, Carl L. & Alexinia Baldwin v. Morgan, J.W., etc. - Brief for Appellants
      - Barr, Charles F., etc. v. City of Columbia, 1961 - Petition
      - Barr, Charles F., etc. v. City of Columbia, & Bouie, Simon v. City of Columbia, & etc. 1963 - Brief for Petitioners
      - Bell, Rachel Lynn v. School City of Gary, Indiana, 1963 - Petition
      - Bell, Robert Mack, etc. v. State of Maryland, 1961 - Petition
      - Bivins, Shirley v. Board of Public Ed & Orphanage for Bibb County - Record on Appeal
      - Bivins, Shirley v. Board of Public Ed & Orphanage for Bibb County - Brief for Appellants
      - Bivins, Shirley v. Board of Public Ed & Orphanage for Bibb County - Brief for Appellees
      - Bivins, Shirley v. Board of Public Ed & Orphanage for Bibb County - Supplemental Record on Appeal
      - Blow, Robert & Ellen Marie Davis v. State of N. Carolina, 1964 - Petition
      - Board of Ed of City of Birmingham v. Armstrong, Dwight & Gibson, Linda Sue v. Harris, Carolyn Eleanor & Roberts, Lawrence v. Stell, Ralph, 1963 - Petition
      - Board of Ed of City of Birmingham v. Armstrong, Dwight & Gibson, Linda Sue v. Harris, Carolyn Eleanor & Roberts, Lawrence v. Stell, Ralph, 1963 - Brief for Respondents
      - Board of Ed of Oklahoma City Public Schools, District # 89 v. Robert L. Dowell & Vivian, 1966 - Brief for Respondents in Opposition
      - Borders, Hilda Ruth v. Dr. Edwin L. Rippy - Appellants' Brief
      - Boson, Sandra Craig v. Rippy, Dr. Edwin L. - Appellants' Reply Brief
      - Bouie, Simon & Talmadge J. Neal v. City of Columbia, 1961 - Petition